<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Overview</title>
  <keywords>
    <keyword translate="true">Introduction</keyword>
    <keyword translate="true">Overview</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1" style="margin-top:19px; line-height:1.0; border-style:single; border-width:1px; border-top:none; border-right:none; border-left:none; tabstops:none;"><text styleclass="Heading1" style="font-family:Verdana; font-size:18pt; vertical-align:baseline; color:#000080;" translate="true">Overview</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><var styleclass="Normal">&lt;%PROGNAME%&gt;</var><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is actively developed and wi</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">th each version we come closer to our goals. With version 5.3 for example, Unicode is supported for creating element names. We have accomplished this by replacing the original text parser with a Unicode compatible parser. These changes make StarUML better to work with, more intuitive and hence easier in use.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Delphi as the principal development language was a main force behind the success of StarUML and now WhiteStarUML. The compiled code is lightning fast, while the language prevents many coding errors and thus provides a huge productivity boost for developers. Thanks to its productivity boost the project could grow and gain popularity while being backed by a team of several developers. The initial developers moved into other ventures and after a number of years of silence, development is now picked up by a new generation of developers, headed by Janusz Szpilewski.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">As with every Open Source project comes a community and by reading this manual, you are part of that community. You can support the </text><var styleclass="Normal">&lt;%PROGNAME%&gt;</var><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> community in different ways.</text></para>
    <list id="1" type="ul" listtype="bullet" formatstring="&#183;" format-charset="SYMBOL_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="ListB" style="font-family:Symbol; font-size:10pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="ListB"><text styleclass="ListB" translate="true">Submit trouble tickets. If you find bugs please submit a ticket at </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="weblink" href="http://sourceforge.net/p/whitestaruml/tickets/" target="_blank" styleclass="ListB" translate="true">&lt;%PROGNAME%&gt; ticket pages</link><text styleclass="ListB" translate="true">. A ticket helps us focus on the problems that affect our users. Before you submit a ticket, please browse through the existing tickets to see if a ticket related to your issue already exists. Workarounds maybe available in the comments of existing tickets.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="ListB"><text styleclass="ListB" translate="true">Contribute to discussions. If you have a question about the application and cannot find an answer in this manual, then ask your question in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="weblink" href="http://sourceforge.net/p/whitestaruml/discussion/" target="_blank" styleclass="ListB" translate="true">&lt;%PROGNAME%&gt; forums</link><text styleclass="ListB" translate="true">. Try to avoid sending emails to the developers, there are many more people available in the forums to answer your questions than there are developers on the project.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="ListBLast"><text styleclass="ListBLast" translate="true">Understand OpenSource. OpenSource is not necessarily free. The source is open for you to read, inspect and suggest or provide improvements to the code. We publish the software under the GNU General Public License, which means you can use the code as the basis for your own fork of free and OpenSource software but you cannot use the code to remove existing copyright holders and sell the software yourself. If you want to make money from this application, please let us share. OpenSource is all about sharing and respect. For more on the license you bind yourself to by using </text><var styleclass="ListBLast">&lt;%PROGNAME%&gt;</var><text styleclass="ListBLast" translate="true">&#32;</text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Appendices" styleclass="ListBLast" translate="true">see the appendices</link></li>
    </list>
  </body>
</topic>
