<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Key to the Guide</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Key to the Guide</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="SubHead"><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="wsuOverview" styleclass="SubHead" translate="true">Overview</link></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Start here if you are new to </text><var styleclass="Normal">&lt;%PROGNAME%&gt;</var><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. This section talks about Model Driven Architecture (MDA) which will be described later in the user guide. You will also find the key features of the application and what it will bring you. Please review the system requirements to make sure that your hardware will be able to run the software, the requirements are remarkably low.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="SubHead"><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="ch02" styleclass="SubHead" translate="true">Basic Concepts</link></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><var styleclass="Normal">&lt;%PROGNAME%&gt;</var><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is not difficult to use, but knowing the basic concepts will help you get started quickly. This is a good section to start reading when you have successfully installed </text><var styleclass="Normal">&lt;%PROGNAME%&gt;</var><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> and want to make full use of the application. Knowing how the basic concepts relate to each other will make reading the rest of the guide easier.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="SubHead"><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="ch03" styleclass="SubHead" translate="true">Managing Projects</link></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">You may skip this section at first, but you will return to this section no mater how good your diagrams already are. This section is all about organizing your project in a sensible way. This section is especially useful if you want to distribute the modeling work over multiple designers and architects. Project leaders should pay attention to this section.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="SubHead"><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Modeling" styleclass="SubHead" translate="true">Modeling</link></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">This section contains general information about how to work with diagrams. The information is applicable to any diagram you want to make. </text><var styleclass="Normal">&lt;%PROGNAME%&gt;</var><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> provides several ways to work with a model and after reading this section you can decide which way is best for what situation.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="SubHead"><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Working_with_Diagrams" styleclass="SubHead" translate="true">Working with Diagrams</link></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If you know what diagram you want to make, this is the section for you.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">This section is the reference for all 11 different diagrams that </text><var styleclass="Normal">&lt;%PROGNAME%&gt;</var><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> supports. Here you will find the explanation of the semantics (the meaning of an element within a diagram) of all elements in the diagrams. Notice for example how class and object have a consistent meaning in all diagrams.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="SubHead"><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="ch06" styleclass="SubHead" translate="true">Program Configuration</link></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">You can make </text><var styleclass="Normal">&lt;%PROGNAME%&gt;</var><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> work for you and in this section you can read how to. You can configure the program as a whole and with increasing detail you can configure almost any part of the application.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="SubHead"><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="ch07" styleclass="SubHead" translate="true">Managing Modules</link></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Modules are the means to extend the functionality of </text><var styleclass="Normal">&lt;%PROGNAME%&gt;</var><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. As </text><var styleclass="Normal">&lt;%PROGNAME%&gt;</var><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> will grow in popularity more modules will become available. Modules may provide new types of diagrams or add some useful functionality not available in the base. This section is for advanced users that need to install or remove a module.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="SubHead"><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="ch08" styleclass="SubHead" translate="true">Generating Code and Documents</link></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The pinnacle of software modeling starts here: round trip software engineering. Create code and documentation from your model and create or update your model from your code. You will use templates to generate code and documentation. Creating or updating the model will require a reverse-engineering module. The basics of this advance topic are explained in this section.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="SubHead"><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="ch09" styleclass="SubHead" translate="true">Verifying Model</link></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">A good model is needed for good diagrams, but eventually it is all about the model. Testing the model is used to make sure it all makes sense within the context of UML. That test is called model verification. Model verification is an advance topic.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="SubHead"><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="pagesetup" styleclass="SubHead" translate="true">Printing Diagrams</link></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Your diagrams are only useful if you can show the diagram to others and can discuss the diagram. Read this section before presenting you work. This section provides some tips and tricks for printing without a headache.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="SubHead"><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="ch11" styleclass="SubHead" translate="true">User-Interface Reference</link></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="ListBLast" translate="true">The complete reference to the user interface. Every detail of the user interface is explained in a general manner. For details how to use those user interface elements in diagrams, refer to the specific diagrams in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Working_with_Diagrams" styleclass="ListBLast" translate="true">Working with Diagrams</link><text styleclass="ListBLast" translate="true"> section.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="SubHead"><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Appendices" styleclass="SubHead" translate="true">Appendices</link></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In the appendices you will find background information. For example, the appendices contain the full text of the licenses under which the software and documentation of </text><var styleclass="Normal">&lt;%PROGNAME%&gt;</var><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is published.</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
